const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which one of the following drugs is an inhibitor of ADP-induced platelet aggregation?","answers":[{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Abciximab","bool":false},{"option":"Clopidogrel","bool":true},{"option":"Tirofiban","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which drug is used for the reversal of heparin?","answers":[{"option":"Enoxaparin","bool":false},{"option":"Protamine sulfate","bool":true},{"option":"Bivalirudin","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Warfarin","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"What is the normal percentage of neutrophils in the adult human?","answers":[{"option":"80 - 90%","bool":false},{"option":"0 - 10%","bool":false},{"option":"20 - 30%","bool":false},{"option":"30 - 40%","bool":false},{"option":"60 - 70%","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"The sensorimotor stage of a child's development is during which period?","answers":[{"option":"Birth to 2 years","bool":true},{"option":"1 to 2 years","bool":false},{"option":"Birth to 6 months","bool":false},{"option":"Birth to 4 years","bool":false},{"option":"2 to 4 years","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following is prolonged by the administration of low-dose heparin?","answers":[{"option":"Activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT)","bool":true},{"option":"Prothrombin time (PT)","bool":false},{"option":"Clotting time","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding time and prothrombin time (PT)","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding time","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which one of the following is not a vitamin K-dependent factor?","answers":[{"option":"Factor II","bool":false},{"option":"Factor VII","bool":false},{"option":"Factor IX","bool":false},{"option":"Factor V","bool":true},{"option":"Factor X","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which one of the following can be best used to describe erythropoietin?","answers":[{"option":"Enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Cofactor","bool":false},{"option":"Glycoprotein","bool":true},{"option":"Coenzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Metalloprotein","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"How would the CD4 (cluster of differentiation 4) cells be classified as?","answers":[{"option":"Granulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Erythrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"T-lymphocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Megakaryocytes","bool":false},{"option":"B-lymphocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"What is the first step for an outbreak investigation?","answers":[{"option":"Verification of diagnosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hypothesize","bool":false},{"option":"Test hypothesis","bool":false},{"option":"Case definition","bool":false},{"option":"Communicating findings","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"What is the composition of hemoglobin A (HbA)?","answers":[{"option":"γ2, ε2","bool":false},{"option":"α2, β2","bool":true},{"option":"α2, δ2","bool":false},{"option":"β2, γ2","bool":false},{"option":"α2, γ2","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following cells become macrophages once they leave the blood circulation to invade the tissue?","answers":[{"option":"Monocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Reticulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following antibodies has a role in type I hypersensitivity?","answers":[{"option":"IgG","bool":false},{"option":"IgM","bool":false},{"option":"IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgE","bool":true},{"option":"IgA","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following processes are involved In the clotting of blood?","answers":[{"option":"Intrinsic pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolytic pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Intrinsic pathway and extrinsic pathway","bool":true},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Extrinsic Pathway","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following tests would be the most appropriate to be recommended to a person having a thalassemic family member?","answers":[{"option":"Urinalysis","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin A1c","bool":false},{"option":"Hb electrophoresis","bool":true},{"option":"None of them","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"What would be the recommended amount of folic acid to be given in thalassemia?","answers":[{"option":"6 mg/day","bool":false},{"option":"7 mg/day","bool":false},{"option":"0.5 mg/day","bool":false},{"option":"1 mg/day","bool":true},{"option":"0.1 mg/day","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"What is the composition of hemoglobin F (HbF)?","answers":[{"option":"α2, δ2","bool":false},{"option":"α2, γ2","bool":true},{"option":"α2, β2","bool":false},{"option":"β2, γ2","bool":false},{"option":"γ2, ε2","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following are among the signs and symptoms of anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Conjunctival redness and pallor","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctival pallor and tachycardia","bool":true},{"option":"Yellow sclera and bradycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphadenopathy and tachycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphadenopathy and bradycardia","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"What does a high reticulocyte count indicate?","answers":[{"option":"Hemolytic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Bone marrow abnormality","bool":false},{"option":"B-12 deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"A 17-year-old boy comes to the clinic with complaints of fatigue and shortness of breath. He has had a history of blood transfusions since childhood and his family history is also positive for blood disorders. His laboratory findings are as follows: Reticulocyte count=3%, increased HbF, low Hb, and MCV. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Thalassemia minor","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle cell disease","bool":false},{"option":"G6PD deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Sideroblastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Thalassemia major","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"What is the embryological origin of the spleen?","answers":[{"option":"Mesenchymal tissue","bool":true},{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Ectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroectoderm","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Where is plasminogen released from?","answers":[{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":true},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the platelets?","answers":[{"option":"Have a nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"2–3 µm in greatest diameter","bool":false},{"option":"Biconvex discs","bool":false},{"option":"Formed from megakaryocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Not true cells","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"What are protein C and S involved in?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-clotting","bool":true},{"option":"Scarring","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Necrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"In which of the following disorders is red blood cell count increased?","answers":[{"option":"Leukocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Polycythemia","bool":true},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombocytosis","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following have a role in the production of both the interleukin-1 (IL-1) and tumor necrosis factor (TNF)?","answers":[{"option":"Osteoblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Keratinocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Women lose a lot of iron during their menstrual cycles. What is the most common cause of iron loss in men?","answers":[{"option":"Malnutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Physiological demands","bool":false},{"option":"Liver disease","bool":false},{"option":"Brain trauma","bool":false},{"option":"GIT bleeding","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which one of the following is the best non-invasive diagnostic test for iron deficiency anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Lipid profile","bool":false},{"option":"Serum ferritin","bool":true},{"option":"Total iron-binding capacity test","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood culture (CBC)","bool":false},{"option":"HbA1c test","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following cells have lobed nucleus, purple-blue-staining granules in the cytoplasm, and release histamine?","answers":[{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":true},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which one of the following is not a screening test?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood culture (CBC)","bool":true},{"option":"Prothrombin time (PT) test","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) test","bool":false},{"option":"Prothrombin time (PT) test and activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) test","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which type of necrosis is found in type III hypersensitivity?","answers":[{"option":"Liquefactive necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinoid necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Caseous necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fat necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulative necrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which one of the following base-pair change is the cause of sickle cell anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Thymine for guanine at 4th codon","bool":false},{"option":"Thymine for adenine at 4th codon","bool":false},{"option":"Thymine for cytosine at 4th codon","bool":false},{"option":"Thymine for adenine at 6th codon","bool":true},{"option":"Thymine for guanine at 6th codon","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which one of the following is the most appropriate test for the diagnosis of spherocytosis?","answers":[{"option":"Thyroid profile","bool":false},{"option":"Prothrombin time","bool":false},{"option":"Osmotic fragility test","bool":true},{"option":"Complete blood culture","bool":false},{"option":"Hb electrophoresis","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"What is prevented by giving a test dose of iron dextran solution before administering the remaining intravenous/intramuscular iron dextran injection?","answers":[{"option":"Fever","bool":false},{"option":"Backache","bool":false},{"option":"Headache","bool":false},{"option":"Anaphylaxis","bool":true},{"option":"Vomiting","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following is an example of type 3 immune complex hypersensitivity?","answers":[{"option":"Contact dermatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Anaphylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Allergies","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":true},{"option":"Hemolytic anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"What is incorrect about X-linked agammaglobulinemia?","answers":[{"option":"Premature B-cells do not produce mature B-cells","bool":false},{"option":"Presents with absent or reduced immunoglobulins","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow does not produce premature B-cells","bool":true},{"option":"It is an X-linked recessive disorder with increased frequency in males","bool":false},{"option":"Defect in BTK gene","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following is the best test for hemolytic anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Low LDH","bool":false},{"option":"Low serum haptoglobin","bool":true},{"option":"Low reticulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Low hematocrit","bool":false},{"option":"Low bilirubin","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following is not nodulated?","answers":[{"option":"Tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Thymus","bool":true},{"option":"Lymph node","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following is included in type II hypersensitivity?","answers":[{"option":"Antibody mediated reaction","bool":true},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotoxic T cells","bool":false},{"option":"Anaphylactic reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Immune complexes deposits","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/blood/2016","question":"Which of the following describes the mechanism of action of warfarin?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibits thrombin","bool":false},{"option":"Acts on hepatocytes to inhibit factor Xa","bool":false},{"option":"Complexes with clotting factors to inhibit thrombus formation","bool":false},{"option":"Acts on hepatocytes and inhibits vitamin K epoxide reductase","bool":true},{"option":"Acts on thrombocytes and inhibits vitamin K epoxide reductase","bool":false}]}]
export default arr